Daniel Shamany

www.danielshamany.com | github.com/dshamany | dshamany@gmail.com | 323-475-8223 | Santa Monica

SUMMARY

I'm a Full Stack Web Developer, who at times works with C++ and Python. I love solving complex problems and enjoy the occasional HackerRank problem. I've spent the past 7 years indulging in coffee, early mornings, and late nights learning and exploring frameworks and beautiful code on GitHub.

SKILLS

React Native | ReactJS | Node.js | Express.js | Next.js | GraphQL | JavaScript | CSS | HTML | Python | Django | MongoDB | MySQL | PostgreSQL | REST APIs | bcrypt | JWT | Socket.io | PassportJS | AWS S3 | AWS EC2 | C++ | Qt | Linux | Mac | Windows | RHEL | Fedora | CentOS | Git | Docker | Kubernetes | Vim | Object Oriented Programming | Data Structures | Design Patterns

EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Software Engineer at CaliberAlpha

Jan. 2018-Present

- Built software for an arduino-based RFID tracker to track on-site worker locations in C
- Built a large portion of a document processing application in C++, utilizing MongoDB
- Utilized NodeJS, ExpressJS, PassportJS for most projects, currently using ReactJS/React Native
- Wrote back-end Python/Django/AWS S3 with CRUD functionality

Software Engineer at Clean Initiative

Jan. 2017-Dec. 2018

- Working knowledge in AWS, iOS, UIKit, MapKit, Swift, and Firebase
- Developed a CRM backend utilizing AWS EC2, SuiteCRM, NodeJS, ExpressJS, REST APIs,
- Developed iOS App for door-to-door canvassing

Growth Specialist at Uber

Apr. 2016-Aug. 2016

- Collecting and assessing data to streamline business operations

PROJECTS

Knowledgebase

- Built using: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MongoDB, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Heroku

Tortuga

- Built using: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, MongoDB, NodeJS, ExpressJS

Watch Collector

- Built using: Python, Django, Materialize, Heroku, PostgreSQL, AWS S3, Heroku

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive at General Assembly

2020

B.S. Business Management at California State University

2015